Jesse Cambon

SUMMARY

Experienced machine learning engineer with expertise in NLP and large language model applications. Broad experience with cloud and machine learning infrastructure. Creator of the R package tidygeocoder.

- Skills: Machine Learning NLP LLMs Software Development Statistics Data Visualization
- Tools: Python R SQL Git Linux Docker AWS Azure

EXPERIENCE

Lead Machine Learning Engineer • Booz Allen Hamilton

Aug 2023 – Present

- Key machine learning developer on a RAG chatbot for searching FDA guidance documents. Led deployment of the app to AWS and implemented key features such as chat history. Utilized AWS Bedrock and Opensearch.
- Built API to provide analysis on medical device documentation using LLMs via AWS Bedrock.
- Led development of a new AI solution for extractive question answering and token classification on GPU cloud compute. Utilized Kubernetes, pytorch, CUDA, and transformers.

Senior Data Scientist • Lighthouse

Mar 2022 – Aug 2023

• Built a flexible framework for training and deployment of large language models. Utilized Azure, pytorch, deepspeed, and Hugging Face libraries. The framework enabled faster experimentation and larger models.

Senior Data Scientist • Embedded Healthcare (acquired by Clarify Health)

Mar 2021 - Feb 2022

- Led analytics efforts to measure the impact of a key company intervention on healthcare utilization.
- Built data pipelines, data infrastructure, and quality assurance algorithms for critical project performance analysis.

Lead Data Scientist • Booz Allen Hamilton

Dec 2017 - Mar 2021

- Served as a technical lead and interim project lead. Managed 1-3 members of a data science team.
- Led the design and implementation of an NLP algorithm that used word embeddings to match employees to internal job opportunities. The algorithm was deployed as a web application for use by all employees and hiring managers.
- Overhauled and redesigned a python AWS Lambda application for enterprise-wide time charge accounting to provide efficient testing with AWS SAM, improved error handling, and smaller dependencies.
- Constructed regression models with Census microdata to analyze characteristics of metropolitan areas that attract immigrants. Presented at the 2018 Joint Statistical Meetings conference in Vancouver on behalf of DHS.

Analytics Consultant • Humana

Aug 2014 – Nov 2017

- Built a predictive model to identify social isolation in a population of 3 million Medicare members.
- Performed observational and randomized studies such as measuring the effects of vaccinations and blood sugar test compliance on medical costs.
- Published research in the American Health & Drug Benefits Journal on the impact of outreaches on out-of-network and emergency room utilization.
- Key analytic contributor to the survey design and analysis for a core company initiative featured in a Harvard School of Public Health case study and published in Population Health Management (2017).

PROJECTS

• Created the R package tidygeocoder which provides a uniform interface for using a variety of geocoding services. Tidygeocoder has over 250,000 downloads and was published in the Journal of Open Source Software (2021).

EDUCATION

- University of Louisville M.Eng. & B.S, Mechanical Engineering, highest honors (2008 2013)
- University of Illinois / Coursera Accelerated Computer Science Fundamentals Specialization
- DeepLearning.Al / Coursera 2 courses: Neural Networks and Deep Learning Improving Neural Networks